# **Austin Schroeder**

(515) 490-8804 || <u>austinsoundy@gmail.com</u> || <u>LinkedIn</u> || <u>Github</u> || <u>Portfolio</u> San Diego, CA

# Introduction

I'm a Software Developer, currently designing and building modern web apps with slick, responsive UIs. I'm obsessed with learning and growing professionally as well as personally.

A long time ago, in a galaxy far far away... I organized multiple aspects of large scale live concerts, tours, and events - specializing in audio engineering. I've decided it's time to take all those skills and experience and make a career change, in hopes of keeping my suitcase unpacked.

# **Technical Skills**

**Front-End** | HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material-UI, React with Hooks, Googling, Adobe Photoshop **Back-End** | Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Firebase, RESTful API design, User Auth

# Experience

# **Coding Projects**

Audio Analyzer Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Canvas, vanilla JavaScript, Parcel bundler

Real Time Analyzer (RTA) web app that will provide a visual display of audio data that is being collected via device mic.

- RGB to HSL conversion to provide coloration for amplitude of specific frequency data
- No libraries or frameworks used

# Remember This Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Material-UI, React, Redux, Node, Express, MongoDB

A responsive web application that enables users to upload an image file or "memory", with a title, creator, short message, and image tags.

- Implemented CRUD API, where users can like posts
- Built to learn React using Hooks and Redux for data store

### Etch-A-Sketch Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Canvas, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop

A web app modeling the Etch-A-Sketch toy to learn about canvas and javascript animation.

- Designed using Photoshop and CSS
- No libraries or frameworks used

#### JavaScript Racer Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Adobe Photoshop

Two player racing game with keyboard controls, sound effects, and score tracking.

- Built to learn jQuery fundamentals as my first app at bootcamp
- Learned web audio API to include background music, sound effects, and winner declaration

#### SASS Portfolio Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, SASS/CSS, JavaScript, Adobe Photoshop

A responsive multi page mock 'tech' portfolio site. Created to learn SASS and try out some humor in my work.

- Used Photoshop to edit custom images
- Completed over the course of 2 days
- No build system. Raw HTML, JS

### InstaClone Repository | Deployed

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Material-UI, React, Firebase

A clone of the popular app, created to learn Firebase, Material-UI, and mobile first design fundamentals.

- Features account creation and user authentication
- Users can add and edit images and comments

#### Cont.

# Knowcap - Full Stack Software Engineer: 2021 - current

Utilizing MERN stack to develop an API that allows companies to agree to pay a service provider based on revenue for a period of time.

- Responsible for implementing Plaid API to add user bank accounts, calculate revenue percentage, find income/revenue.
- Use GitHub Actions as the basis for CI/CD pipeline with GCP
- Implement OpenAPI v3.0.+ for the backend API to service the frontend.
- Use JSON Web Tokens for session authorization
- Implement test driven development using Jest library for API backend
- React Bootstrap is used for components

# Live Concert Production-Independent Contractor: 2011 - 2021

Positions include: Production Manager, Tour Manager, Audio Engineer

- Acts include: Backstreet Boys, Rage Against the Machine, Usher, John Fogerty, Foo Fighters, + many more.
- Created many systems of in-depth efficiency for planning and executing production and travel logistics.
- Planned and maintained budgets of up to \$1,000,000.
- Often required to learn complex digital audio systems and device networking with little time and limited resources
- Managed teams of up to 30, and created enjoyable work environments to keep high morale

### Sound Image, San Diego, CA - Contract Global Account Manager: 2018-2021

- Coordinated and negotiated audio equipment for worldwide arena concert tours
- Built and maintained client relationships via daily communications and networking events
- Brought in an annual average of \$500k+ in sales with budget management

### ECS Jets, Los Angeles, CA - Aviation Advisor/Sales: 2019-2020

- Coordinated aircraft operators with international hubs on logistics and sourcing aircraft
- Sourced and maintained client relationships for a luxury private jet charter service

# Education

#### **General Assembly- Remote: 2021**

#### "Full-Stack MERN, Python, & Django Engineering

- ❖ 650+ hours of full-stack immersive web development with a challenging 12 week curriculum.
- Developed projects using pair programming with focus on full-stack web apps, debugging, and collab using git version control.

#### Full Sail University- Orlando, FL - BA Entertainment Business and Recording Engineering: 2005-2007

- Perfect attendance award.
- ❖ 1st place in university-wide mixing competition.

Sparks Joy: multi instrumentalist musician | video game design | woodworking | building PCs